Haoyu He (He/Him/His)

Khoury College of Computer Sciences
Northeastern University, Boston, MA, 02115

→ +1 (857) 891 3377

→ he.haoy@northeastern.edu

→ haoyuhe.site/

Date of Birth: 12 Feb 1997

Research Vision

My research interests lie within natural language processing and deep learning. Currently, I am broadly interested in the following topics: multimodal understanding, neural information retrieval, language models, few-shot learning in NLP, causal inference in NLP, and low-resource NLP.

Education

2020.6 – 2022.5 Msc in Artificial Intelligence, Northeastern University, Boston, USA.

GPA: 3.42/4.0

Courses: Foundations of Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, Programming Design Paradigm, Human Computer Interaction, Natural Language Processing

2015.9 – 2019.6 **BEng in Computer Science and Technology**, Wuhan University of Science and Technology, Wuhan, China.

GPA: 3.15/4.0

Core Courses:

Algorithm Design and Analysis(A+), Mathematical Modeling (A+), Basics of Numerical Calculation(A), Linear Algebra(A), Probability and Mathematical Statistics(A), Advanced Mathematics(A), Image Processing(A)

Research Experience

Title Persuasive Robots for Health Behavior Change (In Progress)

Supervisor Prof. Dr. Timothy Bickmore

Description In this project, we will explore how a humanoid robot (Pepper) can persuade people to make healthy choices. The robot will interact with people by three modalities: hand gesture, speech, and image on its display. I will mainly focus on building strong conversational ability for the robot and also the study on the effects of dialogue on human behavior change.

Title Automatic Text Simplification (ATS) Using Advanced Deep Learning Techniques (In preparation to NAACL 2022)

Supervisor Prof. Dr. Raman Chandrasekar

Description We proposed the first parametric metrics to directly measure the sentence-to-sentence cohesion and meaning preservation for ATS outputs resorting to pre-trained language models. The two metrics are all reference-free and correlate well to human evaluations. A simple showcase of this project can be found from this temporary link: http://afba-34-221-99-194.ngrok.io/.

Industrial Experience

2020.12–2021.9 **Software Dev Engineer Intern**, Amazon AI Lab, Shanghai, China. Worked as a research intern supervised by Dr. Xingjian Shi. Detailed achievements:

- Devised a meta-learning framework to systematically study the underpinning factors within the process of KD. Unified existing KD objectives as instances of maximizing bounds of the mutual information (MI) and proposed a novel objective function to boost knowledge transfer based on MI estimation. Besides, we proposed the first automated KD algorithm *AutoDistiller* that can recommend a good KD pipeline for a new dataset.
- Aforementioned work was accepted at SustaiNLP 2021, EMNLP workshop.
 Results in this paper are referenced by the course Stanford CS329p, 2021 fall.
- Contributed to the open-source library GluonNLP.
- 2020.5–2020.8 NLP Research Intern, E-Capital Transfer Co., Ltd., Shanghai, China. Studied semantic language models and improved sentence similarity prediction in RASA-based conversational agents, a class of products in this company. Achieved in improving the accuracy of sentence similarity prediction task from 34% to 52% on the business dataset.
- 2019.10–2020.4 **NLP Engineering Intern**, *Ipsos Consulting Co.*, *Ltd.*, Shanghai, China. Applied NLP and machine learning algorithms to develop models that are used to analyse surveys and marketing reports.

Publications

[1] Haoyu He, Xingjian Shi, Jonas Mueller, Sheng Zha, Mu Li, and George Karypis. Distiller: A systematic study of model distillation methods in natural language processing. In *Proceedings of the Second Workshop on Simple and Efficient Natural Language Processing*, pages 119–133, Virtual, November 2021. Association for Computational Linguistics.

Presentations

• Distiller: A Systematic Study of Model Distillation Methods in Natural Language Processing, SustaiNLP, EMNLP, 2021

Skills

- **Programming Languages**: Python, C/C++, Pytorch, Tensorflow.
- Tools & Software: Git, Linux, Ray Cluster, LATEX.
- English: TOEFL: 102, GRE: 152+170+3.5.